kara no kokoro wo terasu mono wa nani?
What brightens up an empty heart?
sakebi tsuzukeru hikari todoku made
I will keep on singing until the light reaches you
falling through the cracks kurayami e ochiteku
Falling through the cracks, Falling into the darkness
anata no sono te o zettai hanasanai
I will never let go of your hand
tell me the story of your life mada michi no tochuu
Tell me the story of your life, We're still on our way
anata o watashi wa zettai akiramenai
I will never give up on you
osaerarenai shoudou nanigenai hibi wa aijyou
Urges I can't suppress, I live for the ordinary days
natsukashii kaze ni furimukeba itsud
When I turn my cheek to a nostalgic wind
emo anata no koe ga suru yo
I always hear your voice
underdog wa wander around
Underdog will Wander around
mawari michi shitemo nigeru yori mashi yo
Even if I take the long way around,
it's better than running away
jibun de jibun o shinjirare nakucha dare wo shinjiru no?
If I can't learn to believe in myself,
then who can I believe in?
hikari ni sono te kazase
Hold up your hand to the light
shining through the clouds kurayami e ochiteku
Shining through the clouds, Falling into the darkness
anata no sono te o zettai hanasanai
I will never let go of your hand
tell me what is on your mind hateshinai yume wo
Tell me what is on your mind,
Chasing the never ending dream
oikake bokura wa zettai akiramenai
We will never give up
kotae no nai jinsei ni kujike sou ni naru kedo
Discouraged by a life without answers, but I...
don’t give it up! keep it up! turn it upside down!
Don't give it up! Keep it up! Turn it upside down!
kokoro wa tsunagatteru yo tatoe tooku hanaretemo
Our hearts will always be connected,
no matter how far apart we may be
tomo ni tomo ni ikiteyukou
Let's share this life together
Naruto Shippuden,
Sasuke's Story:
The Ketsuryugan
You're going to tell me
everything I want to know.
(サスケ)洗いざらい
すべてを吐いてもらうぞ。
I wonder if you can make me?
(風心)できるかな？
Severe Wind Destruction!
猛風大烈破！
クッ！
Severe Wind Destruction!
猛風大烈破！
はぁ～っ！
グッ…。
This isn't over yet!
終わらせない！
はぁ～っ！
うぉ～！
There's no wind.
So this is the eye of the storm!
風がない。 台風の目か。
チッ！
うぉ～！
うぅ…。
Now, tell me everything.
すべてを吐いてもらおうか。
No way.
誰が… クッ クソッ！
Damn it!
What's that?
あれは？
Don't think I'll fall for
the same trick twice!
《二度も同じ手を食うと思うな》
ハァ ハァ…。
So this is Hell Valley...
ここが地獄谷か。
The Chinoike Clan really lived here?
本当に
血之池一族は こんな場所で…。
Yes, we did.
(チノ)本当だよ。
Take a good, long look.
よく見てごらん。
That's proof people lived here.
人が暮らしていた証しだよ。
False suspicion was cast
on them
and the Uchiha Clan forced them
all the way here.
あらぬ疑いをかけられ
うちは一族によって→
ここに閉じ込められた
血之池一族は→
The clan had no choice
but to settle here.
こんな場所で
暮らすしかなかったんだ。
They drank this scalding water,
hunted down whatever birds
they could that flew past...
この煮えたぎる湯を飲み
空飛ぶ鳥を撃ち落とし→
ate the meager grass that grew
in the soil in order to survive.
わずかに生えた草を食らって
生き延びた。
Weary of fighting,
the clan never ventured out
into the outside world,
争いに疲れた一族は
外の世界に出ることもなく→
and scraped out a living,
so I've heard.
ここで細々と暮らしてたらしいよ。
"So I've heard"?
By the time I was old enough
to understand,
らしい？
I was already living
in Oyashiro's mansion.
私 物心ついたときには もう
御屋城の屋敷だったから。
I was told Oyashiro kidnapped me
from Hell Valley... just me.
地獄谷から一人
御屋城にさらわれたんだって。
You were all alone?
一人… だったのか？
え…。
You were all by yourself?
What? You're actually interested?
一人きりだったのか？
How unlike you.
何？ 興味あるの？ 珍しい！
Then let me show you.
だったら 見せてあげるよ。
I was the only one from
the Chinoike Clan.
(チノ)血之池一族は私一人だった。
But there were lots of kids like me
at Oyashiro's mansion
だけど 御屋城の屋敷には
私みたいな子供がたくさんいて→
and we were all forced to train
to become shinobi.
忍の訓練を積まされてたんだ。
What's the matter?
If you don't win, you'll go hungry.
((エン : どうした？ 勝たないと
腹を空かしたままだぞ。
やぁ～っ！
あぁっ！
うわ～っ！
あっ！
You did well, Chino.
(見事だったよ チノ))
And on that day,
Oyashiro brought me to...
(チノ)そして あの日
御屋城が私を連れてったのは→
the Coliseum.
コロシアムだった。
Representing President Kusabi
of Kusabi Real Estate Company
(([マイク]クサビ不動産社長 クサビ様の手札。
and currently on
a record-setting run of no losses!
The Hurricane Kid
who has no mercy...
[マイク]無敗記録 更新中！
情け知らずの台風野郎 風心!!
Fuushin!
And going up against him...
representing Mr En Oyashiro,
who returns after a long absence...
相対しますは 久々のご登場
御屋城エン様の手札。
The Beauty of the Ketsuryugan...
Chino!
麗しの血龍眼 チノ！
I've never heard of
the Ketsuryugan.
Just what kind of power is it?!
[マイク]血龍眼とか
聞いたこともありませんが→
It seems like our audience
is very curious too!
いったい
どんな能力を秘めているのか!?
[マイク]客席の皆様も
興味津々のご様子です。
And now, let's begin!
Ready...
それでは 早速 まいりましょう！
Fight!
レディ！
(観客たち)ファイト！
If you're so eager,
I'll show you my Ketsuryugan.
そんなに見たけりゃ
すぐ見せてやるよ 血龍眼！
I'll blow you away before
you have the chance.
その前に貴様を吹き飛ばしてやる。
Typhoon Style:
High Wind Destruction!
颱遁 強風烈破！
あぁっ！
Whoa... What's this?!
あ～っと！ どうしたことだ!?
Fuushin's just been standing there!
[マイク]風心 先ほどから
突っ立ったままだ！
What's wrong, Fuushin?!
[マイク]いったい どうしたんだ!? 風心。
Did I... just lose?
俺は負けたのか？
Yeah, you lost.
そうだよ 負けたよ。
Can you believe this?!
[マイク]なんという番狂わせ！
The one and only Fuushin has lost to
a young girl in her debut match!
([マイク]あの風心が 初登場の
しかも 幼い少女に敗北した！))
There we go.
You're really strong!
((よっこいしょっと！
Are you being sarcastic?
あんた 強いね！
N-No way!
皮肉か？
うっ そんなことないって。
My eyes are...
S-See... They're special, so...
私の目は…。
ほら 特別だから。
Special, huh?
特別か。
Anyone who possesses
a Kekkei Genkai is special.
血継限界を持つ者は
みんな特別だろ。
Because of this power,
people feared me
and kept their distance.
この力のせいで 人は常に
俺を恐れて距離を置く。
At times, I was shunned
and treated cruelly.
時には疎まれ
邪険にされる。
Even having a past like that
was better than what I had.
そんな過去でも
私よりマシだよ。
What do you mean?
どういう意味だ？
For as long as I can remember,
I've been here.
物心ついたときにはもう
私はここにいた。
I have no memory about
anything before I came here.
だから ここに来る前の記憶なんて
一つもない。
I see.
そうか
幸せなんだな お前は。
You're fortunate.
Me? Fortunate?!
え？ 幸せ？ 私が？
Having memories you don't want
to remember is pointless.
思い出したくもない過去など
持っていてもしかたない。
I was born in the Land of Water.
But it wasn't on the mainland
where the Hidden Mist Village is.
俺は水の国で生まれた。
水の国といっても
霧隠れの里がある本土ではなく→
I was born on
a poverty-stricken island nearby.
周辺の貧しい島だ。
And...
Because of this power,
I was blamed for a typhoon
that struck the island.
そして この力のせいで→
They wanted to get rid of me,
島を襲った大嵐を
俺のせいにされ→
so I was sold off to a rich man
named Kusabi.
厄介払いのため クサビって
金持ちに売りつけられた。
両親によってな。
All I remember about Kusabi's place...
クサビんとこで覚えてんのは
従順であれと→
was the constant torture
even when I was obedient.
But I wasn't averse to fighting
in the Coliseum.
拷問を繰り返されたことだけだ。
だが コロシアムで戦うのは
嫌いじゃなかった。
Because I was able to
demonstrate my strength there.
この力で 俺の強さを
証明できたからな。
And still, I lost to a brat like you.
なのに お前みたいなやつに
負けちまうとは。
I'm sorry I won.
ごめん 勝っちゃって。
You better be!
まったくだ。
Still, I envy you.
それでも私は
あんたが羨ましい。
I don't know what
my mom or dad look like.
I don't why I was born...
父親の顔も母親の顔も
どうして生まれてきたのかも→
or even why I'm alive.
なんで生きているのかも→
I don't have anything!
I don't care how terrible
any past might be.
私には何もない。
It's better than being
empty like me!
それが どんなに
ひどい過去だったとしても→
空っぽの私とは違う！
I...
I just said some terrible things.
私 嫌なこと言ってるよね。
でも 本心なんだ。
But that's how I feel.
Sorry.
ごめん…。
I don't know why, but...
なんでかな。
This is first time I've spoken
about myself to anyone else...
自分のことを こんなふうに
誰かに話したのも初めてなら→
and the first time someone's tears
has actually moved me.
(誰かの涙に
心を打たれたのも初めてだ))
In the end, we were both assigned
to Oyashiro's guard unit...
(チノ)やがて私たちは
御屋城の護衛団に入れられ→
and we started working.
その仕事を手伝うようになった。
And one day, we found it
at the Oyashiro mansion.
そして あの日→
Look, Chino!
御屋城の屋敷で見つけたんだ。
An old historical document
about the Chinoike Clan.
((風心 : 見てみろ チノ))
(チノ)血之池一族のことが書かれた
古い歴史書を。
Let's go, Chino.
Huh?!
If we go to Hell Valley,
((風心 : 行こう チノ。
え？
we may find some of your kin
from the Chinoike Clan.
地獄谷に行けば お前たち
血之池一族がいるかもしれない。
And we might find something
regarding your past!
If you go to Hell Valley,
you won't feel so empty anymore.
お前の過去があるはずだ。
地獄谷に行けば
お前は空っぽじゃなくなる。
But there's no way
Oyashiro will allow it.
だけど 御屋城が
許してくれるはずがない。
We don't need his permission!
(許可なんて必要ない。
え？))
Fuushin and I gathered others
who wanted to get out of
Oyashiro's mansion and escaped.
(チノ)私と風心は
御屋城の屋敷から→
抜け出したいと考えていた
他の連中も誘って脱走した。
We're all free now!
And we ran towards Hell Valley.
((これで 俺たちは自由だ！))
(チノ)そして
地獄谷を目指して走った。
But...
だけど…。
Hey...
You get to live by selling
these crude bamboo knick-knacks.
((おい コラ！ お前らが
こんな粗末な竹細工を売って→
Who do you owe that all to?
Why, we owe it all to you, my lord.
生活できとんのは
誰のおかげや？
– Silence!
– Father!
(イオウ)それはもう 一重に→
領主様のおかげで…。
せやろ！
This is hardly enough!
(アミノ)お父さん！
ああ！
– So... I'll take your daughter in exchange.
– Are you okay, Father?!
こんな量じゃ
納得でけへんなあ。
お父さん しっかりして。
その代わりに→
Amino!
その娘でも もろとこかい！
ヘヘヘ！
ああ！
(イオウ)アミノ！
Wh-Who are you?!
ぐわ～！ イタタ… だっ 誰や！
If you don't want to get hurt,
get lost.
ケガしたくなかったら
さっさと消えな。
Y-Yes...
Hurry, grab him!
は はい！ 早よ連れてけ！
(２人)へい！
S-Sir...
Th-Thank you for saving me.
も… もし！
Think nothing of it.
あ ありがとう。
おかげで助かった。
We just happened to see
what was going on.
Where are you
chivalrous thieves from?
気にするな 見かねただけだ。
Chivalrous thieves?
P-Please! Please continue
to protect us!
あんたら どこの義賊だ？
義賊？
た… 頼む！
これからも わしらを→
We were hailed
as chivalrous thieves.
(守ってくれんか？))
So we adopted the name,
the Lightning Gang
(チノ)
義賊に祭り上げられた私たちは→
and worked for
the sake of nearby villages.
雷光団を名乗って
近隣の村のために働いた。
We were treated like heroes.
Every time we appeared,
the villagers welcomed us.
まるで英雄扱いだった。
姿を見せるたび
村の人たちは歓迎してくれた。
They gave us food and shelter.
Everyone was kind.
ご飯や宿を提供してくれた。
Sorry that we haven't been
able to go to Hell Valley.
みんな優しかった。
((悪いな
地獄谷に行けなくなっちまって。
That's okay.
I can go to Hell Valley anytime.
大丈夫だよ。
地獄谷には いつでも行けるもん。
For now, let's work hard
for these people.
(今は
この人たちのために頑張ろう))
We owed allegiance to no one,
others were at our mercy.
(チノ)どこにも属さず
猛威を振るう私たちを見て→
Seeing this, some shinobi villages
tried to use us.
逆に利用しようとする
忍里も現れた。
During the reign of
the previous Mizukage,
先代 水影の時代→
the Hidden Mist were
our valued clients.
霧隠れも
私たちのお得意さんだった。
That same thing happened then.
We went after a Feudal Lord
あのときも そう。
who was taking money
from the unfortunate.
弱者からカネを搾取する
小国の大名を襲えって。
Oh come on. What's the matter?
You mustn't, my lord.
((のう よいではないか。
ハハハ いけません殿。
A-Are you the infamous—?!
うわぁ！
キャー！
Yeah, we're the Lightning Gang.
お前たちが 噂の!?
Get him.
そう 雷光団だ。 やれ。
W-Wait... please.
As long as you pay up,
we won't hurt you.
うわ～！ ま 待ってくれ 頼む！
That's as far as you'll go.
カネさえ出せば乱暴なことはしない。
そこまでだ。
Shinobi...?!
The Hidden Mist?!
忍!? あっ…。
I see... You want to get rid of us.
And not only that,
霧隠れ！
you intend to create a direct relationship
with the Feudal Lord.
そうかい 俺たちを処分し→
Th-Thank you for saving me.
なおかつ 腐れ大名とのパイプも
作ろうって魂胆か。
You're correct.
ありがとう 助かった。
(そのとおり))
It's horrible, isn't it?
But, what's worse was...
(チノ)ひどい話でしょ？
けどね もっとひどかったのは…。
Just for a while...
Let us rest here.
Please go somewhere else.
((一時でいい 休ませてくれ。
What?
If we harbor you,
we'll end up paying dearly for it!
(イオウ)よそに行ってくれ。
え？
お前たちをかくまったら
わしらまで被害を被るかもしれん。
We have no intentions
of troubling the village!
む… 村に
迷惑をかけるつもりはない。
We'll leave right away!
Just because you take money
from others and give it away,
すぐに出ていく。
don't think you can do
whatever you want!
他人から巻き上げたカネを
配っただけで→
(よく ぬけぬけと
そんなことが言えるな！))
Every village was the same.
They wouldn't even give us water.
(チノ)どの村も 水の１杯さえ
分けてくれなかった。
One by one,
our wounded comrades died.
１人 ２人…
傷ついてた仲間は死んでいき→
Eventually, it was just
Fuushin and me.
私と風心は ２人きりになった。
There's nowhere else we can go.
((もう行くとこ
なくなっちゃったね。
Yes, there is.
Huh?
(いや ある。
え？))
So we... finally made it
to Hell Valley.
(チノ)そして私たちは→
地獄谷に たどり着いた。
I'm empty, after all.
Chino?!
((やっぱり私は空っぽなんだ。
チノ!?
I can't remember anything!
My father, my mother...
何も思い出せない！
I can't remember anyone's faces!
自分の父親も母親も→
Coming here didn't solve anything,
after all.
一族の顔だって！
I still don't know why
I was born or why I'm alive!
ここへ来たって
わかるはずなかったんだ。
どうして生まれてきたのか
なんで生きてるのかなんて！
Pursuers from the Hidden Mist!
霧隠れの追っ手か。
Chino!
チノ！
Let go, you damn—!
Owww!
放せ この野郎！
Chino...!
いてて…。
チノ！
W-What the hell is this?!
うっ！ な 何だ これ!?
What's wrong?
ど どうした!?
Chino!
うわっ！
(風心)チノ！
Chino!
Chino, are you all right?
チノ？
I... didn't know I could do this.
チノ 大丈夫か!?
私 こんなことができたんだ。
So... that was the true power
of the Chinoike Clan?
じゃあ 今のは
血之池一族の本当の力。
I'll get my revenge!
(復讐してやる！))
sayonara arigatou
Good bye, thank you
koko kara habatakou
We're flying away from here
karappo no tenohira nigirishimete sa
Our empty hands squeezed tight
namida ja nagasenai tashika na omoi ga atta
Not even tears could wash away these feelings
kagiri aru sekai e fumidasu yo
We're stepping out into a world with limits
ashita moshi bokura ga koko kara kietemo
Even if we're suddenly gone tomorrow
kawari nante hoka ni mo irundesho?
There would be others who could replace us, right?
jishin nante hajime kara motte wa inai kedo
We were never confident to begin with
akiramerarenainda
But we can't seem to give it up
isso
What if...
zenbu o suteraretara
We just abandon everything and call it quits?
motto raku ni naru ka na
Would things be easier?
sonna imeeji hitotsu de
That image alone
matataku ma ni toozakatteyuku mirai
was enough to grab on hold to the future
dakishimeta
that was quickly fading away
sayonara arigatou
Good bye, thank you
muchuu de habatakou
We're flying away with everything we got
kagiri aru sekai no sono naka ni
Into a world with limits
sayonara arigatou sayonara arigatou
Good bye, thank you
kanarazu mata aeru sono basho de
We'll definitely meet again, back there
The Uchiha Clan was used up
and absorbed by the Leaf.
So why do you go
so far for them?
I have a friend now who
shares in my pain.
He also hopes the whole world
will become like that too.
A world like that...
is impossible!
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
“Sasuke's Story: Sunrise, Part 5:
The Last One”
A heart that hopes for that,
connects me to the Leaf!